<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-1003" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Tolls of Madness</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Southwest Virginia's <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Rocky Horror Picture Show</i> shadowcast, with semesterly shows in Haymarket Theatre. </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><p class="- topic/p ">A classic college experience is attending chaotic movie showings, and at Virginia Tech this crucial tradition is handled by Tolls of Madness. Every year, they put on a few showings of <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">The Rocky Horror Picture Show</i> in Haymarket Theatre, while acting along with the movie and encouraging the audience to shout things out and participate. It's loud, raunchy, and can be utterly startling to people who aren't used to this kind of event, but that is the point.</p><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Tolls of Madness performers onstage doing <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">The Rocky Horror Picture Show</i>, from the Tolls of Madness GobblerConnect</title><image alt="&#34;Rocky Horror Picture Show&#34; cast members performing a kick line." width="300" href="4ffbbf75-e481-4446-9e12-cbbc59d969a163d7f885-6fa3-4c39-a49d-14a48deb2847.jpeg" class="- topic/image "/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">Tolls of Madness travels all around Southwest Virginia during the Halloween season, with a rotating cast so that everyone in their organization gets to be onstage as well as helping out behind the scenes. They encourage audience participation, selling bags of things to use and throw throughout the performance, as well as holding "the underwear run" during part of the movie. Those who have never attended the event before have their foreheads marked in lipstick with a V for "virgin," and have the opportunity to participate in "the virgin games," a series of silly and suggestive contests before the show starts to warm up the audience to the nature of the show.</p><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">An example of a <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Rocky Horror Picture Show</i> attendee outfit for "Chappel Roan Night", by Evvy Fite</title><image width="300" href="20241018_164257.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Student Evvy Fite posing in their costume for "Rocky Horror Picture Show."</alt></image></fig><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">The lipstick "V" applied to all new show-goers, photo by Evvy Fite</title><image width="300" href="20241018_225512.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Student Evvy Fite showing off the lipstick "V" marking her as a first-time attendee of Virginia Tech's "Rocky Horror Picture Show" performance.</alt></image></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The Virginia Tech community comes out in droves to see the show, dressed in costumes either reminiscent of the movie itself, or in line with the costume theme for each showing. Themes include topics like "leather and lace" or "dress like Chappel Roan," and result in a vibrantly-dressed crowd ready for chaos. The show is a massive community-bonding experience that sweeps you up in the energy, and whether it's right up your alley or you take a moment to get used to the tone, everyone should experience it, whether during their years at Tech or on a return visit after graduation.</p></body></topic>