<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-2965" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Naturally Sharp</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">A semesterly show by one of Virginia Tech's all-male a capella groups, usually held in Haymarket Theatre.</shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><p class="- topic/p ">Another favorite semesterly activity is the Naturally Sharp concert, held towards the end of each semester, usually in Haymarket Theatre. Each show has a theme, played out through goofy videos at the opening of each act, and complimented by costumes and marketing that fit the theme. Recent themes have included Batman, <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Total Drama Island</i>, <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Avatar: The Last Airbender</i>, and a 1920s murder mystery.</p><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Poster for "Singing Bad," from Naturally Sharp Instagram</title><image href="singingbad.jpeg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">The poster for the Naturally Sharp show "Singing Bad," featuring members of Naturally Sharp posing and dressed up like characters from "Breaking Bad."</alt></image></fig><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Poster for "Total Natty Island," from Naturally Sharp Instagram</title><image href="totalnattyisland.jpeg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">The poster for the show "Total Natty Island," featuring members of Naturally Sharp dressed like characters from the show "Total Drama Island."</alt></image></fig><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Poster for "Navatar: The Last Airbender," from Naturally Sharp Instagram</title><image href="navatar.jpeg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">The poster for the show "Navatar: The Last Airbender," featuring members of Naturally Sharp dressed up as and posed like characters from "Avatar: The Last Airbender."</alt></image></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The guys of Naturally Sharp, or Natty, rehearse several times a week each semester to prepare a selection of a capella songs, carefully chosen to show off their voices and coordinate with the show's theme. As part of auditions, the group selects certain members as soloists, giving them a chance to show off their voices individually.</p><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Photo from "Total Natty Island," taken by Evvy Fite</title><image width="300" href="20231111_193104.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">A photo from the audience of Naturally Sharp's performance titled "Total Natty Island."</alt></image></fig><p class="- topic/p ">Natty shows are fun and vibrant, and they consistently sell out Haymarket Theatre. Tickets are $7 in advance and $10 at the door. They always have a loud contingent of alumni in attendance, ready to hop up onstage for the alumni song at the end of the night.</p><p class="- topic/p ">Though the music is fantastic and the energy high, it is worth mentioning that Naturally Sharp shows can be a bit of an overwhelming sensory experience, which should be taken into consideration before attending. Additionally, they stop between songs for speeches and raffles, which can be annoying to some people.</p><p class="- topic/p ">Despite this, however, each Naturally Sharp concert is a fantastic experience, and a great way to relax for an evening. Current students and alums alike can have a fantastic time and leave with music in their ears.</p></body></topic>