<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-4100" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">SPAP Sketch Comedy</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">A semesterly sketch comedy show, produced entirely by undergrad students, held in various performance venues.</shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><p class="- topic/p ">SPAP Sketch Comedy at Virginia Tech puts on a free comedy show each semester, open to the public of Virginia Tech and Blacksburg. Held at various spaces around campus, such as the Creativity and Innovation District Performance Hall and Studio Theatre, SPAP shows draw a large crowd from all over campus and often sell out one or both nights.</p><p class="- topic/p ">SPAP is entirely student-led, from the writers' room to the stage, and allows students who haven't had the change to do theatre before to step out of their comfort zone and have a moment in the spotlight. They receive consistent positive reviews from both Virginia Tech students and the performers' parents, as well as a decent number of views on the organization's YouTube channel.</p><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Members of SPAP rehearsing the sketch "Fishmongerer" for the Fall 2024 show. Photo by Evvy Fite.</title><image width="300" href="20241007_184938.jpg" class="- topic/image "/></fig><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">SPAP actors rehearsing the finale of the Fall 2024 show on the stage of Squires Studio Theatre. Photo by Evvy Fite.</title><image width="300" href="20241207_100059.jpg" class="- topic/image "/></fig><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">SPAP member Alessandria in a dress run of the sketch "Sleight of Hand" in the Fall 2024 show. Photo by Evvy Fite.</title><image width="300" href="20241007_200002.jpg" class="- topic/image "/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">Although still growing in popularity, SPAP is starting to gain recognition on campus. With their free shows being held at the end of each semester, they provide the perfect opportunity to relax before exams. They are enjoyed by audience members of all ages and stages of life, so if you're on campus when a SPAP show is happening, take 90 minutes out of your weekend and laugh away your problems!</p></body></topic>