<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-7683" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Virginia Tech Philharmonic Orchestra</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Virginia Tech's symphony orchestra, putting on several shows each semester in the Moss Arts Center.</shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><p class="- topic/p ">The Virginia Tech Philharmonic Orchestra, under the direction of Mathias Elmer, is a modern symphony orchestra comprised of music majors and non-music majors from all over Virginia Tech. With a highly selective audition process every semester, it's an accolade to perform with this ensemble.</p><p class="- topic/p "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">A performance of the Virginia Tech Philharmonic Orchestra</title><image alt="An image of the Virginia Tech Philharmonic Orchestra performing on the stage of the Anne and Ellen Fife Theatre at the Moss Arts Center at Virginia Tech." href="hq720.jpg" class="- topic/image "/></fig>They put on several public shows each semester in the Moss Arts Center. Tickets go for $10-$12 dollars, and the experience is well worth the money. They perform a collection of modern and classic pieces, sometimes with one piece lasting for the entire show.</p><p class="- topic/p ">The Virginia Tech Philharmonic Orchestra has gained enough renown that composers often come to them with a debut piece. Last year, they played the world premiere of "Mosaic for Earth," a collection of fourteen songs featuring the Philharmonic, operatic soloists, choirs of both children and adults, and more. Dwight Bigler, the composer, was awarded The American Prize in Composition.</p><p class="- topic/p ">A lot of young people think of orchestra music as boring or annoying, but they haven't seen a good symphony orchestra. In the Anne and Ellen Fife Theatre at the Moss Arts Center, the music surrounds and envelops you, and you can tell how much work went into this.</p><p class="- topic/p ">The orchestra is a highly underrated Virginia Tech campus event that everyone should experience at some point during their years at VT. If you are in town during a Virginia Tech Philharmonic Orchestra performance, it is a must-see!</p></body></topic>